# Osama Abdelrahman

Mobile Application Developer

O UAE, Abu Dhabi.

**+971586623199** 

@Osamaabdalla.com

## **SUMMARY**

I have seven years of experience in creating cross-platform mobile applications especially using React native, and also did many Full-stack web-based applications creating frontend, backend, and APIs. Moreover, I have experience in preparing and processing Data as I spent two years creating projects for companies in Data Science field using machine learning and deep learning models.

## **OBJECTIVE**

To enhance my skills, capabilities, and knowledge in an organization that recognizes the value of hard work and trusts me with responsibilities and challenges.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Created and contributed in more than 40 cross-platform mobile application for both Android and iPhone, with more than 80 web applications and admin dashboards. Moreover I contributed in 6 real projects in Data Science field.

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Data Science and Analytics

Malaysia, 2020

Universiti Sains Malaysia (USM).

Study areas:

- Machine Learning
- Business Intelligence & Decision Analytics
- Multimodal Information Retrieval
- Enabling Technologies, Infrastructures For Big Data
- Big Data Storage And Management
- Research, Consultancy, And Professional Skills
- Consumer Behavioral And Social Media Analytics
- Principles & Practices Of Data Science & Analytics and Visualization

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Sudan, 2012

Omdurman Islamic University (OIU)

Study areas:

- Operations Research and Artificial Intelligence
- Web. Programming and Software Engineering
- Computer Networks and Expert Systems
- Information System Management and Security & Analysis
- Relational Databases and Data Structure

## **SKILLS**

| •   | Cross Platform Mobile Apps .7yrs |
|-----|----------------------------------|
| **  | Front-end Development 7yrs       |
| **  | Back-end Development 6yrs        |
| *** | Machine Learning 2yrs            |
| •   | Data Science 2yrs                |
| *** | Deen learning 1yrs               |

## PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

| **       | HTML (8 Years) 5/5         |
|----------|----------------------------|
| <b>*</b> | CSS (8 Years) 5/5          |
| *        | JavaScript (7 Years) 4/5   |
| *        | TypeScript (6 Years) 4/5   |
| *        | PHP (6 Years) 4/5          |
| *        | Python (2 Years) 3/5       |
| *        | Angular V1&2 (2 Years) 3/5 |

## **DATABASES**

| *** | MySQL ( / Years) 4/5  |
|-----|-----------------------|
| •   | MongoDB (4 Years) 4/5 |

## FRAMEWORKS

| 1 11/ | MILITOTINO                 |
|-------|----------------------------|
| *     | React Native (5 Years) 4/5 |
| *     | Meteor (5 Years) 4/5       |
| *     | React (5 Years) 4/5        |
| *     | Ionic (3 Years) 4/5        |
| *     | Laravel (3 Years) 3/5      |
| **    | TensorFlow (1 Years) 3/5   |

## **TOOLS**

| VSCode   | Spider   | GitHub  |
|----------|----------|---------|
| Terminal | Anaconda | Tableau |
| XCode    | Postman  | Jupyter |

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Mobile Application Developer

Nov 2020 - Nov 2021

#### **ACCENTURE**

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Create functional design deliverables (including page-flow, business logic, validations, etc.
- Manage requirement confirmation & design workshops.
- Create/Enhance Mobile applications.
- Perform System Testing on the web-based application.
- Support SIT / UAT testing & to perform bug fix.
- Perform code build and deployment of the completed codes into the development and testing environment.

### Data scientist, Internship

Feb 2020 - Jun 2020

#### MOLEX (MALAYSIA) SDN. BHD

Penang, Malaysia.

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Develop and deploy statistical and machine learning models for data analysis to discover any hidden patterns.
- Collaborate with product management and engineering departments to understand the assembly production needs and devise possible data science solutions.
- Communicate results and ideas to key decision-makers.
- Implement new statistical methodologies as needed for specific models or analysis to ensure the final product quality.
- Optimize joint development efforts through appropriate database use and project design.
- The deployed models results showed a significant improvement in the products quality and a feasible reduction in the rejection rates.

### Web & Mobile Apps Developer

Apr 2018 - Jan 2019

#### TOWARD LEADERSHIP

Medina, Saudi Arabia.

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Developing frontend architecture for clients.
- Designing user interactions on Applications pages.
- Developing backend for clients applications.
- Creating and defining databases schema.
- Ensuring cross-platform optimization for mobile phones.
- Ensuring responsiveness of applications.
- Collaborate with graphic designers for final designs delivery.
- Designing and developing APIs between Frontend and Backend.
- Communicating with the projects manger to meet the consumer needs.

### **OPERATING SYSTEMS**

MAC Windows Linux

#### CONTENT MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

WordPress | OpenCart | Django

#### **DEV OPS**

AWS DigitalOcean OpenStack

#### OTHER SKILLS

AJAX JQuery Node Js Redux

RESTfull NPM Agile Scrum

#### **LANGUAGES**

ENGLISH ...... AdvancedARABIC ..... Native

### **WEBSITES & SOCIAL LINKS**

Website: Osamaabdalla.com
GitHub: @Osamaabdalla

#### **PARTICIPATIONS**

Participated in the record event of the most participants in a Hackathon is 2,950 was achieved by Saudi federation for cyber security, programming, and drones Saudi Arabia, which was verified in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, on August 2018. Our participation involve two mobile applications to help in improving Hajjij (pilgrims) journey while they are in the holy places

## **INTERESTS**

Video Games => Flight simulation

## Web & Mobile Apps Developer

Nov 2015 - Mar 2018

#### MARKETING-IT SOLUTIONS

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Creating and maintaining customers' mobile applications.
- Developing dashboards for mobile applications.
- Developing front and back end website applications.
- Creating servers and databases for functionality.
- Ensuring cross-platform optimization for mobile phones.
- Ensuring compatibility of the mobile applications.
- Working alongside managers and graphic designers in the company for web and mobile apps designs.
- Designing and developing APIs between Dashboards and Apps.

Web Developer Oct 2013 - Oct 2015

#### **HOWISTART**

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Creating and maintaining website applications and admins dashboards.
- Developing back end for customers web applications.
- Creating servers and databases based on customer's needs.
- Ensuring cross-platform optimization for websites pages.
- Ensuring compatibility of the websites applications.
- Creating and managing Amazon web services for websites.
- Monitor and maintain any possible vulnerabilities to avoid hacking.
- Managing websites security and as a result the company got Trustwave certificate to offer credit card payments through their website.
- Integrate the payment gateways such as 2checkout, Stirpe, and Paypal.